https://help.rei.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/50

Privacy Policy
Skip Navigation
Your browser either does not have JavaScript enabled or does not appear to support enough features of JavaScript to be used well on this site.
Women’s
Kids’
Women’s
Kids’
Patagonia
Herschel Supply Co.
Cotopaxi
Herschel Supply Co.
Effective Date:  October 1, 2020
This Privacy Policy ("Policy") explains how Recreational Equipment, Inc. and our subsidiaries and affiliates (collectively, "REI," "we" or "us") collect, use and share information about you when you access or use our websites or other online or mobile services or applications ("Services"), shop in our stores, attend our events, outings, or trips, or otherwise interact with us. We may supply different or additional notices of our information practices specific to certain programs or activities. We may also provide different notices of our information practices with respect to certain subsidiaries or affiliates, in which case this Policy will not apply. For purposes of this policy, personal information includes "personal data" and similar terms as defined under applicable privacy laws.
REI may change this Policy from time to time. If we make changes, we will notify you by revising the Effective Date above and, in some cases, we may provide you with more prominent notice (such as adding a statement to our homepage or sending you a notification). We encourage you to review this Policy whenever you access our Services or otherwise interact with us to stay informed about our information practices and the choices available to you.
Contents
Collection of Information
Use of Information
Sharing of Information
Social Sharing Features
Your Choices
Advertising and Analytics Services Provided by Others
Your California Privacy Rights
Additional Disclosures for Individuals in Europe
Contact Us
Collection of Information
Information You Provide to Us. We collect information you provide directly to us. For example, we collect information when you become a member; make a purchase or rental from us; access and use our Services (including when you write a review or participate in other interactive areas of our Services); create an online account or profile; sign up for or participate in contests, promotions, sweepstakes, customer experience research, surveys, mailing lists, events, outings or trips; engage with us via social media platforms; and when you email, call, or otherwise communicate with us.
The types of information we may collect include your name, address, phone number, email address, ZIP code, photos, videos, social media usernames, payment information, demographic information, information about your interests, outdoor activities, and preferences, information about your fitness condition and physical characteristics, the content you post to the interactive areas of our Services, and any other information you choose to provide. If you sign up for an REI event, outing, or trip, or in other limited circumstances, we may collect additional information from you, such as medical, health and disability information, passport information, dietary requirements, and emergency contact information.
In some cases, we may also collect information you provide about others, such as when you provide emergency contact information, purchase a gift card for someone and request that we deliver it electronically, decide to purchase and ship products to someone, or create and share a gift registry. We will use this information to fulfill your requests and will not send communications to your contacts unrelated to your requests, unless they separately consent to receive communications from us or otherwise engage with us.
Information We Collect Automatically. When you access or use the Services or transact business with us, we automatically collect certain information about you, including:
Transaction Information:  When you purchase, rent or return a product, or register for events, outings, or trips, we collect information about the transaction, such as product details, purchase price, and the date and location of the transaction.
Log and Usage Information: We obtain information about the device you use to access our Services and your use of our Services, including the type of browser you use, hardware model, operating system and app version, mobile network information, IP address, unique device identifiers, access times, pages viewed, items placed in your cart, links clicked, browsing behavior, and referring URL (the webpage you visited before navigating to our Services).
Location Information: In accordance with your device permissions, we may collect information about the precise location of your device. For more details, please see "Your Choices" below.  We may also collect information about your approximate location each time you access our Services.
Information Collected by Cookies and other Tracking Technologies: We and our third-party service providers may use cookies, clear GIFs (also known as web beacons, web bugs or pixel tags), and other tracking technologies to collect information about you and your interaction with our Services, including information about your browsing behavior, purchase behavior, and other engagement with the Services. Most web browsers are set to accept cookies by default, but you can usually change your browser settings to remove or reject cookies. For more information about the types of cookies we use and our reasons for using them, as well as your choices concerning cookies, please see our Cookie Policy.
Information We Collect from Other Sources. We may also receive information about you from other sources and combine or link that with information we have about you. For example:
We receive information from our partners that provide or lead REI experiences (events, outings and trips), such as contact information and feedback participants provide.
We collect change-of-address information, demographic information, and information about consumer preferences, interests and opinions from third party sources.
If you create an account or access our Services using credentials from a third-party social media platform (such as Facebook), we have access to certain information from that platform, such as your name, email address, friends list and public profile information, in accordance with the authorization procedures determined by that platform.
We collect content you share publicly in connection with our products, services or campaigns, including photos, videos and profile information.
If you apply for certain co-branded financial products, we receive certain information from the financial institution we partner with, including whether your application was approved or denied, account closure information, and aggregated information about your transactional history.
We may collect information about you from other users if they choose to share that information with us via the Services, such as if they purchase gifts for you.
Information We Infer or Derive About You. We may use or combine personal information that you provide, that we collect automatically, or that we obtain from other sources to derive or infer additional personal information about you. For example, we may infer that you are looking to purchase new hiking gear based on your website browsing behavior and past purchases, or we may use your IP address to estimate your general location.
Use of Information
We use the information we collect about you to provide, maintain, and improve our Services and the other interactions we have with you. For example, we use the information we collect to:
facilitate and improve your in-store and online shopping experience;
administer your membership and communicate with you about your membership and the Co-op (including information about your dividend, special offers only available to members, annual meetings, board elections, and the Co-op's stewardship initiatives);
provide and deliver products and services, process transactions and returns, and send you related information, including confirmations, receipts, invoices, customer experience surveys, and recall notices;
manage your accounts with us, host forums and interactive areas of our Services, provide technical support (including to debug and troubleshoot), and send you technical notices, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages;
detect, investigate and prevent fraudulent transactions and other illegal activities and protect the rights and property of REI and others;
respond to your comments and questions and provide customer service;
communicate with you about REI and partner products, services, offers, contests, promotions, sweepstakes, surveys and customer experience research, advocacy and stewardship initiatives, news, events, outings, trips, and other information we think will be of interest to you (for information about how to manage promotional communications, please see "Your Choices" below);
comply with our legal and financial obligations;
monitor and analyze trends, usage and activities;
in connection with our Services, stores and experiences;
tailor the content and information that we send or display to you, offer location customization and personalized recommendations, help, and instructions, and otherwise personalize your experience while using our Services;
provide advertising and marketing targeted toward your interests;
process and deliver contest, promotion and sweepstakes entries and prizes;
link or combine with other information we receive from third parties to help understand your preferences and provide you with personalized service; and
carry out any other purpose conveyed to you at the time the information was collected.
Transfer of Information to the U.S. and other Countries
We are based in the United States and process and store the information we collect in the U.S. If you are based outside the U.S., we transfer your personal information to, and process your personal information on, servers located in the U.S., a jurisdiction that may not provide equivalent levels of data protection as your home jurisdiction.
Sharing of Information
We may share personal information about you outside of REI as follows or as otherwise described in this Policy:
with service providers, vendors, contractors, or agents who complete transactions or perform services on our behalf, such as those that assist us with our business and internal operations like shipping and delivery, rentals, payment processing, fraud prevention, customer service, gift cards, experiences, co-branded financial products, personalization, marketing, and advertising;
when you participate in the interactive areas of our Services (such as by creating a profile, posting comments and other content, reporting trail conditions, or writing reviews), certain information about you may be displayed publicly on our Services and also may be distributed on third-party sites. For example, your photos, videos, stories, posts, comments, product reviews, product questions and answers, wish lists, information about your participation in outdoor activities and any other content or information you choose to provide will be shared with users of our Services. In the case of trail conditions, we will also share certain information with third party organizations like rangers or other trail service organizations;
at your direction, including when you submit a product review using a third party service, create an account or access our Services using credentials from a third party social media platform (such as Facebook), or otherwise direct REI to share your personal information with a third party, or take any action on the Services that are subject to the terms of use and privacy policy of a third party;
in connection with, or during negotiations of, a corporate business transaction, such as a merger or acquisition of all or a portion of our business to another company, joint venture, corporate reorganization, insolvency or bankruptcy, financing or sale of company assets;
in response to a request for information if we believe disclosure is in accordance with any applicable law, regulation or legal process, including lawful requests by public authorities to meet law enforcement or national security requirements;
if we believe your actions are inconsistent with our Terms of Use or other agreements or policies, or to protect the rights, property, and safety of REI, our members, our customers, or any other persons;
between and among REI and any current and future parents, affiliates, subsidiaries, and other companies under common control and ownership; and
with your consent.
We may also share aggregated or de-identified information, which cannot reasonably be used to identify you.
Social Sharing Features
The Services may offer social sharing features or other integrated tools, which let you share actions you take on the Services with other media, and vice versa.  The use of such features enables the sharing of information with your friends or the public, depending on the settings you establish with the third party that provides the social sharing feature.  For more information about the purpose and scope of data collection and processing in connection with social sharing features, please visit the privacy policies of the third parties that provide these features.
Your Choices
Your Account Information. You may update or correct your online account information by logging into your online account and updating your information or by calling 1-800-426-4840 (US and Canada) or 1-253-891-2500 (outside the US and Canada)  . You may also email us at privacy@rei.com if you wish to deactivate your online account, but note that we may retain information about you for legitimate business purposes or as required by law. If you would like to update or correct your membership information, you may do so by completing our Update Your REI Membership Information form or by calling 1-800-426-4840 (US and Canada) or 1-253-891-2500 (outside the US and Canada) .
Promotional Communications. You may opt out of receiving promotional communications from REI by following the instructions in those communications or changing your preferences via http://www.rei.com/help/subscriptions.html. If you opt out of receiving promotional communications, we may still send you non-promotional emails, such as emails about your purchases, account, membership or our ongoing business relations, including information about your dividends and Co-op's initiatives and activities.
Location Information. The settings of your Internet browser or mobile device may allow you to stop sharing your precise location with REI or others. You can also stop our collection of location information in connection with our mobile applications by following the standard uninstall process and removing all REI applications from your mobile device.
Mobile Push Notifications/Alerts.  With your consent, we may send promotional and non-promotional push notifications or alerts to your mobile device.  You can deactivate these messages at any time by changing the notification settings on your mobile device.
Advertising and Analytics Services Provided by Others
We allow third parties to provide analytics services and serve advertisements on our behalf across the web and in mobile applications. These third parties may use cookies, web beacons, and other technologies to collect information about your use of the Services and other websites, including your IP address, web browser, mobile network information, pages viewed, time spent on pages, links clicked, and conversion information. In some cases, the information in these cookies and other technologies may be linked to other data we collect about you, such as your email address, which we may share in hashed or encrypted form. This information may be used by REI and these third parties to analyze and track data, determine the popularity of certain content, deliver advertising and content targeted to your interests on our Services and other websites and mobile applications, and better understand your online activity. For more information, please see our Cookie Policy. For more information about interest-based ads, or to opt out of having your web browsing information used in this way, please visit www.aboutads.info/choices. For individuals in the EEA, please visit http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/.
We may also work with third parties to serve ads to you as part of a customized campaign on third-party platforms (such as Facebook or Google). As part of these ad campaigns, we or third-party platforms may convert information about you, such as your email address and phone number, into a unique value that can be matched with a user account on these platforms to allow us to learn about your interests and to serve you advertising that is customized to your interests. Note that the third-party platforms may offer you choices about whether you see these types of customized ads.
Your California Privacy Rights
Consumers residing in California are afforded certain rights with respect to their personal information under the California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”). If you reside in California, this section applies to you.
Collection, Use and Disclosure of Personal Information: In the preceding 12 months, we have collected the following categories of personal information: identifiers, characteristics of protected classifications under California or U.S. law, commercial information, Internet or other electronic network activity, geolocation data, audio and visual information, professional and employment related information, education information, inferences drawn about your preferences, and other personal information that is described in Section 1798(e) of the California Civil Code. For examples of the precise data points we collect and the sources of such collection, please see “Collection of Personal Information” above. We collect personal information for the business and commercial purposes described in the “Use of Personal Information” section above. We share personal information with the categories of third parties described in the “Sharing of Personal Information” section above.
In the preceding 12 months, we have disclosed the following categories of personal information for business and commercial purposes to the following categories of recipients:
Category of Personal Data
Categories of Recipients
Identifiers
Cloud Service Providers, Payment Processing Companies, Analytics Companies, Fraud Prevention Companies, Marketing Companies, Fulfillment Partners, User Engagement Partners
Characteristics of Protected Classifications Under California or U.S. Law
Cloud Service Providers, Marketing Companies, Fulfillment Partners, Fraud Prevention Companies
Commercial Information
Cloud Service Providers, Fulfillment Partners, Payment Processing Companies, Marketing Companies, Fraud Prevention Companies
Internet or Other Electronic Network Activity Information
Cloud Service Providers, Analytics Companies, Marketing Companies, User Engagement Partners, Fraud Prevention Companies
Geolocation Data
Cloud Service Providers, Analytics Companies, Fraud Prevention Companies, Marketing Companies
Audio, Electronic, or Visual Information
Cloud Service Providers, Fraud Prevention Companies
Professional or Employment Information
Cloud Service Providers, Analytics Companies, Marketing Companies
Education Information
Cloud Service Providers, Analytics Companies, Marketing Companies
Inferences
Cloud Service Providers, Analytics Companies, Marketing Companies
Personal Information Described in Section 1798.80(e) of the California Civil Code
Cloud Service Providers, Fulfillment Partners, Fraud Prevention Companies
We do not sell personal information to third parties.
Your Rights: Subject to certain limitations, you have the right to (1) request to know more about the categories and specific pieces of personal information we collect, use, and disclose for a business purpose, (2) request deletion of your personal information, (3) opt out of any “sales” of your personal information that may be occurring, and (4) not be discriminated against for exercising these rights. You may make these requests by submitting a request online or by contacting customer service at 1-800-426-4840. We will verify your request by asking you to provide information related to your recent interactions with us, such as information regarding a recent purchase. If you would like to use an authorized agent registered with the California Secretary of State to exercise your rights, we may request evidence that you have provided such agent with power of attorney or that the agent otherwise has valid written authority to submit requests on your behalf. We will not discriminate against you if you choose to exercise your rights under the CCPA.
Notice of Financial Incentives: We offer various financial incentives. For example, we may provide discounts, gift cards, or other benefits to customers who sign up to receive our marketing emails or participate in a survey. When you participate in a financial incentive, we collect personal information from you, such as identifiers (like your name and email address) and commercial information (like your purchase history). You can opt into a financial incentive by following the sign-up or participation instructions provided, and, for any ongoing benefits, you have the ability to opt-out at any time, such as by following the unsubscribe instructions in our promotional emails or contacting us at privacy@rei.com. In some cases, we may provide additional terms and conditions for a financial incentive, which we will provide to you when you sign up. The value of your personal information is reasonably related to the value of the offer or discount presented to you.
Additional Disclosures for Individuals in Europe
If you are located in the European Economic Area (“EEA”), the United Kingdom, or Switzerland, the following section applies to you.
Legal Basis for Processing. When we process your personal information, we will only do so when:
We need to use your personal information to perform our responsibilities under our contract with you, for example to deliver products that you ordered from us.
We have a legitimate interest in processing your personal information. For example, if you are a customer, we may process your personal information to send you marketing communications, to communicate with you about changes to our Services, and to provide, secure, and improve our Services.
We find such processing is necessary to comply with our legal obligations.
We have your consent to do so. When your consent is the legal basis for our processing, you may withdraw such consent at any time.
Data Retention. We store the information we collect about you for as long as is necessary for the purpose(s) for which we collected it or for other legitimate business purposes, including to meet our legal, regulatory, or other compliance obligations.
Data Subject Requests. Subject to certain limitations, you have the right to access personal information we hold about you and to ask that your personal information be corrected, erased, or transferred. You may also have the right to object to, or request that we restrict, certain processing. If you would like to exercise any of these rights, please send an email message to privacy@rei.com or call Customer Service at +1 (253) 891-2500. You may also update your online account information by logging into your online account or through the other methods described in the "Your Choices" section.
Questions or Complaints.  If you have a concern about our processing of personal data that we are not able to resolve, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Data Protection Authority where you reside. Contact details for your Data Protection Authority can be found using the links below:
For individuals in the EEA: https://edpb.europa.eu/about-edpb/board/members_en
For individuals in the UK: https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/
For individuals in Switzerland: https://www.edoeb.admin.ch/edoeb/en/home/the-fdpic/contact.html
Contact Us
If you have any questions, comments or concerns about this Policy or about our privacy practices, please call Customer Service at 1-800-426-4840 (US and Canada) or 1-253-891-2500 (outside the US and Canada) or send an email message to privacy@rei.com. You may also direct your privacy-related comments or questions to the following address:
Recreational Equipment, Inc.
Attention: Privacy Officer
6750 S. 228th Street
Kent, Washington 98032
Email this page
Recipient Email
*
Your Email
*
Reddit
Was this helpful?
Yes
No
Please tell us how we can make this answer more helpful.
Email *Required
Your Feedback *Required
Please note that a response will not be received for feedback submitted through this form. Should you require additional assistance, please contact us using a different method.
Answers others found helpful
Terms of Use
Contact Us
Cookie Policy
Return Policy
Affiliate Program
Contact Us
Check out our COVID-19 FAQs or type your question into the "How can we help?" search bar.
Mon-Fri:
5am - 10pm PT
Sat-Sun:
6am - 9pm PT
Email us
An REI representative will respond to you as soon as possible
1-800-426-4840
Mon-Fri, 5am-10pm PTSat-Sun, 6am-9pm PTInternational:1-253-891-2500
Looking for a store near you?
Store Locator
How are we doing?
Give us feedback on this page.
Sign up for REI emails
Co-op offers, events & cool new gear
Email
Error:
Is your email address correct?
Sign me up!
REI Privacy Policy
Thank you!
Check your inbox for your first email from REI. We'll send you a few emails every week. You can easily unsubscribe at any time.
System Maintenance
The newletter sign-up system is currently down for maintenance.
Who We Are
At REI, we believe that a life outdoors is a life well lived. We've been sharing our passion for the outdoors since 1938.Read our story
Become A Member
Join the REI Co-op community to get an annual dividend, access exclusives and give back. Lifetime membership is just $20. Learn more and join us
Apply For REI Co-op Mastercard®
Earn a $100 REI Gift Card when you apply, get approved and make any purchase within 60 days of card approval.Details
Find answers online anytime.
© 2020 Recreational Equipment, Inc. All rights reserved. REI and the REI Co-op logo are trademarks of Recreational Equipment, Inc.
